everyone has a favorite muscle they like
to train for women it's typically the
glutes for men it's the pecs the biceps
the delts now picture the best pump you
ever achieved you know you looked in the
mirror like
damn what would you pay for that pump to
be permanent now unfortunately i can't
teach you how to get a permanent glute
pump but until i figure out a way
this is the next best thing
[Music]
the pump if you work out you love it
everybody loves it you want to achieve a
pump
in your favorite muscles for some people
it's the biceps others it's the glutes
for me it's actually the delts you know
i actually
think about this a lot and the way i
look
after i've pumped my delts and traps up
i would pay a million dollars to just
look like that around the clock and i
look in the mirror
after i'm done pumping out my delts i'm
like why can't i just
get to a point where i actually look
like this but in all these years i can't
now for most bros they'd pick an upper
body muscle like the pecs
the bias the delts but for the vast
majority of women they want a glute pump
as a matter of fact
i have women clients who confess
to pumping up their glutes prior to like
a party or
going to the beach or somewhere where
they have to wear a bikini or they have
to wear
an event where they have to wear a dress
so that led me to start thinking of well
what is the best way to pump up the
glute so in this video i'm going to show
you my preferred protocol for maximizing
a glute pump but before all that
let's talk about the physiology of the
muscle pump
the greatest feeling you can get in a
gym or the most satisfying feeling you
can get in the gym
is the pump let's say you drain your
biceps
blood is rushing into your muscles and
that's what we call the pump
your muscles get a really tight feeling
like your skin is going to explode any
minute you know it's really tight it's
like somebody blowing
air into into your muscle it just blows
up and it feels
different it feels fantastic when you're
lifting weights
and the contractions are intense enough
the muscular contractions will actually
occlude the veins but the arteries
continue to pump blood
into the muscles now just so i don't
butcher this i'm actually going to read
straight from an article that i
published with my buddy brad schoenfeld
he knows the science better than i do
and this article was titled the muscle
pump
potential mechanisms and applications
for enhancing hypertrophic adaptations
resistance exercise has been shown to
induce acute alterations of intra and
extracellular water balance the extent
of which is dependent on the type of
exercise and intensity of training the
model for these changes in fluid balance
has been described as such during
intense muscular contractions the veins
taking blood out of the working muscles
are compressed whereas arteries continue
to deliver blood into the working
muscles thereby creating an increased
concentration of intramuscular blood
plasma this causes plasma to seep
out of the capillaries and into the
interstitial spaces the buildup of fluid
in the interstitial spaces brings about
an extra cellular
pressure gradient which triggers a flow
of plasma back into the muscle i.e
reactive hyperemia this enhanced
reperfusion results in a phenomenon
commonly referred to by sport scientists
as
cellular swelling and by bodybuilders as
the pump
whereby muscles become engorged with
blood the pump is magnified by
resistance exercise that relies heavily
on anaerobic glycolysis
particularly bodybuilding style training
that involves moderate to higher
repetitions with limited rest intervals
such exercise results in a substantial
accumulation of metabolic byproducts
including lactate
and inorganic phosphate which in turn
function as osmolytes and thereby draw
additional fluid into the cell so now
you understand the physiology of the
pump but it may actually lead to
hypertrophy and here's how okay right
here is a theoretical schematic for
cellular swelling mechanisms of action
on muscle hypertrophy so you've got
exercise induced cell swelling and this
causes osmo sensors to detect a stretch
on the cell membrane now the cell
perceives this to be a threat
on its integrity so it initiates
anabolic and anti-catabolic processes
which ultimately leads to muscle protein
accretion now the jury is still out as
to whether
it does in fact lead to long-term muscle
growth some of the top hypertrophy
experts think it does
for example brad schoenfeld others are
more skeptical but it's actually pretty
difficult to devise a training study
examining this phenomenon now i've
talked about the physiology of the pump
i've talked about how it might
lead to increased muscle growth over
time but this video is more for vanity
all right you're going to party you're
going to a photo shoot
you're pumping up backstage for
competition you want your booty to be as
big as humanly possible
what can you do if you're pumping up
backstage chances are they're not going
to have a hip thruster and a barbell and
plates
but you get the point if i was trying to
get my glutes as engorged with blood as
humanly possible
or i was taking pictures of a bunch of
my clients and i needed their butts to
be round and full
here's what i'd give them so in this
video you're going to see my client tori
perform three sets of 20
triple banded barbell hip thrust pulses
now what this means is she's got a glue
loop around her knees
she's doing a barbell hip dress but
she's got a glute loop on each side
connected to the hip thruster so the
glute loop around her knees is pulling
inwards she's got to use her glutes to
keep her knees out
gravity acting on the barbell is pushing
down on the hip so she's got to create
hip extension torque
to raise the bar and as you raise the
bar the glute loops attached to the hip
thruster are stretched
generating further resistance and
requiring more output out of the glutes
to reach a full lockout now by only
doing a pulse you're keeping constant
tension on the glutes
you're not allowing any blood to escape
and you're going to do three sets of 20
reps
making sure to achieve full hip
extension on each rep resting
60 to 90 seconds between sets now after
you finish those three sets you take the
glute loop
around your knees off you also remove
the glute loops
from the hip thruster so torey's fatigue
we've got 130 pounds on the bar the
glute loops probably added another 100
150 pounds but now we take those off so
it's 130 pounds and tori's gonna get an
extra 20 reps just using the 130 but
making sure she squeezes like crazy at
the top of every rep on the last rep
she's gonna do a five second iso hold
now this goes immediately into
putting the glute loop back around the
knees and performing
30 30 30 bands seated hip abduction the
first 30 is performed leaning back
the second 30 reps in an upright fashion
and the last 30 reps leaning forward so
as you can see
this protocol lasted under 15 minutes
it's designed to pack a big punch in a
short amount of time to trap as much
fluid as possible
in your glutes so your glutes will be
engorged with blood it'll be full
and voluptuous and hopefully it lasts
for a couple of hours you know
i feel like my pumps dissipate quickly
but some of my clients
swear that they can feel the glute pump
for half the day now also in the corner
i'm going to show some footage of my
client lorita
also performing a similar protocol but
instead of using a barbell she used
a thruster band same exact concept there
except i had to do 30 reps
now unfortunately uh laurita and tori
both only grew a half an inch on their
glutes on this protocol
but i've had other clients gain a full
inch and some of my online clients
swore that they achieved a two inch
glute pump from the same protocol
i've heard all about this two inch glute
pump i've just never measured it myself
on a client but even though tory and
lorita only put a half an inch on their
glutes
they felt it their glutes were swollen
and we took pictures right afterwards
and you can see for yourself check out
these booties they're poppin
so if you are interested in achieving
the biggest glute pump humanly possible
now you have a protocol you can try now
if you're one of the lucky folks that
bought a bunch of equipment from my
company bc strength
and you've got a hip thruster and the
glute loops etc then good for you
chances are you're going to perform this
at a gym
you know you just have a standard bench
here's how you can set up bands
at a commercial gym i know this is
different but it's the next best thing
[Music]
so there you have it the best darn glute
pump in existence
give it a try and let me know what you
think okay if you liked the video
please make sure to hit like please
leave me a comment and definitely make
sure you're subscribed to my channel
i've got a lot of good things coming in
2021. now if this video intrigued you
and you would like to train under my
system using my principles
then i invite you to click on the link
below and subscribe to booty by brett
and join the thousands of other happy
members who are seeing amazing results
you